A Guide to the Clifford Currie Collection on Colvin Run Mill, 1967-2003 (bulk 1968-1972)
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Clifford Currie Collection on Colvin Run Mill, 1967-2003 (bulk 1968-1972)
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 06-45
0.75 linear feet
The Clifford Currie Collection on Colvin Run Mill consists of 0.75 linear feet and spans the years 1967-2003, the bulk of which dates from 1967-1972. The collection contains Currie’s handwritten logbooks, oversized engineering design drawings, and 422 slides taken during the restoration of Colvin Run Mill from 1968-1972.
Currie, Clifford Randolph (1918-2004)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Friends of Colvin Run Mill in 1999 and gifted to Fairfax County Public Library’s Virginia Room in 2003.
Historical and Biographical Information
Clifford Randolph Currie, an expert Canadian millwright engineer, was born in Round Hill, Alberta, Canada on December 23, 1918. In addition to rebuilding Colvin Run Mill, Currie reconstructed the Roblin’s Mill in Toronto’s Black Creek Pioneer Village in 1960.
Colvin Run Mill, a c.1811 merchant’s mill built in Great Falls, Virginia, was owned by the Sheppard, Carper, Powell, and Millard families throughout a 120-year period. In 1965, the Fairfax County Park Authority acquired the Colvin Run Mill property through condemnation proceedings from Bernard B. Bailey who had purchased the mill in 1934. The Park Authority hired John B. Campbell, a well-known mill restorationist, to make plans to restore the mill and assess its condition. It soon became evident that restoration would not be a simple project due to the mill’s dilapidated state and structural deficiencies. Campbell recommended that the Park Authority hire Clifford Currie to direct the mill’s restoration.
As superintendent, Currie directed the daily work, prepared the engineering drawings, and carried out the restoration plan for Colvin Run Mill from 1968-1972. Currie documented the painstaking restoration efforts through logbooks, drawings, and slides which are included in this collection. Construction moved at a slow pace due to Currie’s insistence on crafting and using authentic tools and materials necessary for recreating a 19th century mill. After four years of construction, the Park Authority re-hired John Campbell as millwright-engineer to complete Currie’s work in May 1972.
The restored Colvin Run Mill officially opened to the public on July 8, 1972. Currie successfully rebuilt the building as an authentic working 19th century mill with functioning water wheel and interior gearworks. That same year, the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors designated the mill and surrounding property as the Colvin Run Mill Historic Overlay District in order to protect the mill’s environment and the visual character of Colvin Run Road.
In September 1975, the Virginia Chapter of the American Institute of Architects presented the Fairfax County Park Authority with an award for excellence in craftsmanship for their restoration of the mill. The U.S. Department of Interior listed Colvin Run Mill on the National Register of Historic Places in 1977. In May 2001, ASME International designated the mill as a Historic Mechanical Engineering Landmark.
Clifford Currie died on May 3, 2004 in Fort Pierce, Florida.
Scope and Content
The Clifford Currie Collection on Colvin Run Mill consists of 0.75 linear feet and spans the years 1967-2003, the bulk of which dates from 1967-1972. The collection contains Currie’s handwritten logbooks, oversized engineering design drawings, and 422 slides taken during the restoration of Colvin Run Mill from 1968-1972. Included in the collection are typed transcriptions of the logbooks prepared by Marjorie Lundgard in 2002 and of the slide collection indexed by Bob Lundegard and Nick Yannarell in 2003.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Colvin Run Mill; Currie, Clifford R. (1918-2004); Fairfax County Park Authority; Historic buildings -- Virginia -- Fairfax County; Mills and mill-work -- Virginia -- Fairfax County
Container List
- Series 1: Logbooks, 1968-2003
  - Transfer letter from Friends of Colvin Run Mill, 2003 February 3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Book. “Summary of Clifford Currie’s Notes on the Restoration of Colvin Run Mill May 21, 1968-April 6, 1972” transcribed by Marjorie Lundegard April 15, 2002, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Log Book No. 1, 1968 May 21 - 1968 September 10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Log Book No. 2, 1968 September 9 - 1968 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Log Book No. 3, 1968 December 9 - 1969 April 5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Log Book No .4, 1969 April 7 - 1969 November 25 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Log Book No. 5, 1969 November 26 - 1970 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Log Book No. 6, 1970 April 20 - 1971 January 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Log Book No. 7, 1971 January 4 - 1971 August 30 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Log Book No. 8, 1971 August 31 - 1972 April 6 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series 2: Engineering Drawings, 1968-1972
  - Clifford Currie Engineering Drawings, Set 1. West, East, North/South elevations, door & windows frames, window sash [5 sheets], 1968 October 10 - 1969 January 22 (Box Oversize, Folder Drawer)
  - Clifford Currie Engineering Drawings, Set 2. Detail views of water wheel and shaft bearings [6 sheets D1-D6], 1971 February 26 - 1971 June 8 (Box Oversize, Folder Drawer)
  - Clifford Currie Engineering Drawings, Set 3. Sectional views of mill interior [3 sheets], 3 small drawings of wheel details (undated), 1 small drawing of shoring jack details (1968), 1968, 1972 March 29 (Box Oversize, Folder Drawer)
  - Blue line reproduction of Sets 1 thru 3, Undated (Box Oversize, Folder Drawer)
  - Blue line reproduction of Sets 1 thru 3, Undated (Box Oversize, Folder Drawer)
  - Photocopy of Sets 1 thru 3 [18 sheets], Undated (Box Oversize, Folder Drawer)
- Series 3: Slides, 1967-2003
  - Jim Bell, 1971 November (Box 2, Folder 1-1)
  - James Watt & Dick Martin, 1971 November (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Cliff & Red Hott, 1975 September (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Jim Bell & me, 1971 November (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - Start Mill Construction, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
  - County Building Sign, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
  - Old Entry Sign, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-7)
  - 1st Day at the Mill, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-8)
  - Start Mill Construction, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-9)
  - Wood Wall, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-10)
  - Head Wall, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-11)
  - Decisions - Decisions decisions, what was original?, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-12)
  - Problems - Back to the drawing board, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-13)
  - Clearing - Clearing for construction, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-14)
  - Starting Work - Starting work at Colvin Run Mill, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-15)
  - Observations, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-16)
  - Cliff Currie - Cliff-Pre-Construction in the front door, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-17)
  - Cliff Currie - Cliff-"Built in 1794", 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-18)
  - Removal - Remove Mill Machinery, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-19)
  - Old Gearing, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-20)
  - Old Gearing, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-21)
  - More Figures, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-22)
  - Currie's Desk - My desk to start re-construction, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-23)
  - Office - My trailer office, 1971 February (Box 2, Folder 1-24)
  - Clearing Site, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-25)
  - Start Excavation, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-26)
  - Clearing - Clearing for excavating for tail race, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-27)
  - Start Excavation, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-28)
  - Soil Testing - Soil testing compaction-100 blows=1inch, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-29)
  - Bracing Mill, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-30)
  - Rock Strata - Shoring and testing rock strata, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-31)
  - Shoring, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-32)
  - 1st Canopy, 1968 June (Box 2, Folder 1-33)
  - Bracing Mill, 1968 September (Box 2, Folder 1-34)
  - Shoring, 1968 October (Box 2, Folder 1-35)
  - Brickwork, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-36)
  - 1st Canopy, 1968 August (Box 2, Folder 1-37)
  - Cog Pit Shoring, 1968 October (Box 2, Folder 1-38)
  - Under Pin, 1970 October (Box 2, Folder 1-39)
  - Under Pin, 1970 October (Box 2, Folder 1-40)
  - Under Pin Forms, 1970 October (Box 2, Folder 1-41)
  - Underpin, 1970 October (Box 2, Folder 1-42)
  - Underpin, 1968 October (Box 2, Folder 1-43)
  - Excavate Waterwheel Pit, 1968 October (Box 2, Folder 1-44)
  - Waterwheel Pit - 1st Canopy-Excavate Waterwheel Pit, 1968 October (Box 2, Folder 1-45)
  - Excavate Waterwheel Pit, 1968 October (Box 2, Folder 1-46)
  - Excavate Waterwheel Pit, 1968 October (Box 2, Folder 1-47)
  - Excavate Pit - Prepare Headwall, 1968 October (Box 2, Folder 1-48)
  - Cavern for Waterwheel, 1968 October (Box 2, Folder 1-49)
  - Rockwork - Old Headwall and Rockwork, 1968 October (Box 2, Folder 1-50)
  - Waterwheel Pit - Start New Construction, 1968 October (Box 2, Folder 1-51)
  - Waterwheel Pit - New Construction, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-52)
  - Mill Bracing - 1st Canopy, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-53)
  - Waterwheel Pit - Waterwheel Pit Rockwork, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-54)
  - Waterwheel Pit - Complete Pit Rockwork, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-55)
  - Waterwheel Pit - Waterwheel Pit Rockwork, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-56)
  - Foundation Brickwork, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-57)
  - Start Bricks, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-58)
  - 1st Canopy Bricks, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-59)
  - Brickwork, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-60)
  - Brickwork - Start Brickwork-Start 2nd Canopy, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-61)
  - 2nd Canopy- 2nd Canopy-Mill Bracing for Restoration, 1969 February (Box 2, Folder 1-62)
  - 2nd Canopy, 1969 February (Box 2, Folder 1-63)
  - 2nd Canopy, 1969 February (Box 2, Folder 1-64)
  - 2nd Canopy, 1969 February (Box 2, Folder 1-65)
  - 2nd Canopy, 1969 February (Box 2, Folder 1-66)
  - Brick Canopy-2nd, 1969 April (Box 2, Folder 1-67)
  - Building Quonset, 1969 February (Box 2, Folder 1-68)
  - Construction Quonset, 1969 February (Box 2, Folder 1-69)
  - Quonset, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-70)
  - Quonset Storage, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-71)
  - Snow - Heavy Snow on Quonset, 1970 February (Box 2, Folder 1-72)
  - Logging - Logging at Reston for CRM, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-73)
  - Timber - Timber from Reston Golf Course Const., 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-74)
  - Lumber - Mill Lumber, 1971 February (Box 2, Folder 1-75)
  - Lumber - Lumber for Mill, 1971 February (Box 2, Folder 1-76)
  - Timber - Cliff & Timber for Mill, 1971 February (Box 2, Folder 1-77)
  - Timbers, 1971 February (Box 2, Folder 1-78)
  - Timbers, 1971 February (Box 2, Folder 1-79)
  - Headwall - Old Rock Headwall and Bricks, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-80)
  - Brickwork - Brickwork and 2nd Canopy, 1969 April (Box 2, Folder 1-81)
  - Brickwork - Repair Old Brickwork, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-82)
  - Brickwork, 1969 April (Box 2, Folder 1-83)
  - Brickwork, 1969 April (Box 2, Folder 1-84)
  - Brickwork, 1969 April (Box 2, Folder 1-85)
  - Brickwork Decisions, 1969 April (Box 2, Folder 1-86)
  - Brick Fireplace, 1969 April (Box 2, Folder 1-87)
  - Brickwork, 1969 April (Box 2, Folder 1-88)
  - New Basement Fireplace, 1969 April (Box 2, Folder 1-89)
  - Beam on Fire, 1970 February (Box 2, Folder 1-90)
  - 1st Floor Fireplace, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-91)
  - Inside Fireplace, 1969 April (Box 2, Folder 1-92)
  - Fireplace - Outside Corner at Fireplace, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-93)
  - Fireplace - Rebuilding Basement Fireplace Outside, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-94)
  - Colvin, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-95)
  - Brickwork, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-96)
  - Brickwork - Bricks-Up Flue, 1969 April (Box 2, Folder 1-97)
  - Brickwork - Brick Walls - Open, 1969 April (Box 2, Folder 1-98)
  - Brickwork, 1969 October (Box 2, Folder 1-99)
  - Brickwork, 1969 October (Box 2, Folder 1-100)
  - Brickwork - Roots in Brickwork, 1969 October (Box 2, Folder 1-101)
  - Brickwork - Roots in Old Bricks, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-102)
  - Brickwork - Brickwork-Window Frame, 1969 October (Box 2, Folder 1-103)
  - Brickwork - Mall Bridge Prop, 1969 October (Box 2, Folder 1-104)
  - Tail Race - Tail Race at Bridge, 1969 October (Box 2, Folder 1-105)
  - Brickwork - Bricks at Window Frame - 2nd Floor Ceiling, 1969 October (Box 2, Folder 1-106)
  - Brickwork, 1969 October (Box 2, Folder 1-107)
  - Brickwork - Wall Reaching 1st Floor, 1969 June (Box 2, Folder 1-108)
  - Brickwork - Wall Reaching 1st Floor, 1969 June (Box 2, Folder 1-109)
  - Brickwork - Wall Reaching 1st Floor, 1969 June (Box 2, Folder 1-110)
  - Brickwork - Dangerous Brick Walls, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-111)
  - Brickwork - Easton-Bricks Near 1st Floor Ceiling, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-112)
  - Brickwork, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-113)
  - Brickwork - Removed 2nd Canopy, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-114)
  - Tail Race - Start Tail Race, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-115)
  - Bridge Race, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-116)
  - Bridge Race, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-117)
  - Tail Race, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-118)
  - Tail Race, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-119)
  - Tail Race, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-120)
  - Tail Race - Drag Line Tail Race, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-121)
  - Tail Race, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-122)
  - Tail Race, 1969 September (Box 2, Folder 1-123)
  - Tail Race, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 1-124)
  - Flood - Flood at CRM, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-125)
  - Chimney - Start Chimney, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 1-126)
  - Chimney, 1969 September (Box 2, Folder 1-127)
  - Chimney, 1969 September (Box 2, Folder 1-128)
  - Chimney - Completed Chimney, 1969 September (Box 2, Folder 1-129)
  - Roof & Gables - Scaffold for Roof & Gables - Sandblast, 1969 September (Box 2, Folder 1-130)
  - Trees - Remove 2 Trees, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 1-131)
  - Trees - Remove Trees, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 1-132)
  - Trees - Remove Trees, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 1-133)
  - Trees - 2 Trees, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 1-134)
  - Trees - Remove 2 Trees, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 1-135)
  - Trees - Remove Trees (2) by Waterwheel, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 1-136)
  - Bricks - Old Bricks in Roots from Old Mill Wall, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 1-137)
  - Trees - 2 Trees, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 1-138)
  - Trees - Bricks in Roots, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 1-139)
  - Trees - 1889 Tree Twig-Bricks in Roots-86 Years Old, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 1-140)
  - CRM, 1970 January (Box 2, Folder 2-1)
  - Roof - Start Roof & Gables, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 2-2)
  - Gables - Repair Gables, 1970 January (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Gables - Repair Gables, 1970 January (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
  - Top Floor - Top Floor & Roof, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 2-5)
  - Top Floor - Top Floor & Roof, 1970 January (Box 2, Folder 2-6)
  - Attic, 1970 January (Box 2, Folder 2-7)
  - Head Race - Trucks for Rock-Head Race, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 2-8)
  - Head Race Head Race-Start Clearing Trees, 1969 August (Box 2, Folder 2-9)
  - Head Race, 1969 September (Box 2, Folder 2-10)
  - Head Race, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 2-11)
  - Head Race, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 2-12)
  - Head Race - Head Race Park, 1969 September (Box 2, Folder 2-13)
  - Head Race, 1969 September (Box 2, Folder 2-14)
  - Head Race - Head Race Park, 1969 September (Box 2, Folder 2-15)
  - Head Race - Pour Head Race, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 2-16)
  - Head Race - Head Race Rock, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 2-17)
  - Head Race - Seeding Head Race Park, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 2-18)
  - Head Race - Head Race Park, 1970 January (Box 2, Folder 2-19)
  - Head Race - Why Rocks at Head Race, 1970 January (Box 2, Folder 2-20)
  - Head Race - Head Race Rocks, 1970 January (Box 2, Folder 2-21)
  - Head Race, 1970 January (Box 2, Folder 2-22)
  - Head Race - Why Rocks - Head Race, 1970 January (Box 2, Folder 2-23)
  - Head Race - Head Race Rocks, 1970 January (Box 2, Folder 2-24)
  - Head Race - Head Race Rocks, 1970 January (Box 2, Folder 2-25)
  - Head Race - Head Race Rocks, 1970 January (Box 2, Folder 2-26)
  - Head Race - Head Race Nears Completion, 1970 January (Box 2, Folder 2-27)
  - Head Race, 1970 January (Box 2, Folder 2-28)
  - Head Race - Head Race Spillway, 1970 January (Box 2, Folder 2-29)
  - Head Race - Head Race Park, 1970 January (Box 2, Folder 2-30)
  - Head Race - Seeding, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 2-31)
  - Head Race - Seeding Head Race Park, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 2-32)
  - CRM - Snow During Construction at CRM, 1970 February (Box 2, Folder 2-33)
  - CRM - Sand Blasting, 1970 June (Box 2, Folder 2-34)
  - CRM - Sand Blasting, 1970 June (Box 2, Folder 2-35)
  - CRM - Sand Blasting, 1970 June (Box 2, Folder 2-36)
  - CRM - Sand Blasting, 1970 June (Box 2, Folder 2-37)
  - Water Wheel - Water Wheel Tree, 1970 March (Box 2, Folder 2-38)
  - Water Wheel - Water Wheel Tree, 1970 March (Box 2, Folder 2-39)
  - Water Wheel - Water Wheel Shaft- Cliff Currie, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-40)
  - Water Wheel - Turning Water Wheel Shaft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-41)
  - Water Wheel - Turning Water Wheel Shaft, 1970 October (Box 2, Folder 2-42)
  - Water Wheel - Currie Turning Water Wheel Shaft, 1970 October (Box 2, Folder 2-43)
  - Water Wheel - Eston-Shaft Water Wheel, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-44)
  - Water Wheel - Boring Water Wheel Shaft, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-45)
  - Water Wheel - Boring Water Wheel Shaft, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-46)
  - Water Wheel - Mortising Water Wheel Shaft, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-47)
  - Water Wheel - Currie Mortising for Water Wheel Shaft Arms, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-48)
  - Water Wheel - Water Wheel Shaft Mortises, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-49)
  - Water Wheel - Ready for Gudgeon Cuts, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-50)
  - Water Wheel - Shaft Mortises, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-51)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Shaft Turning Lathe, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-52)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Shaft Gudgeon Mortise, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-53)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Shaft Ready for Gudgeon, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-54)
  - Water Wheel - Good All around View of Mill Shaft Gudgeon, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-55)
  - Water Wheel - Cutting with Cross Cut Saw for Gudgeons, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-56)
  - Water Wheel - Gudgeon Cuts, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-57)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Shaft Construction, 1971 April (Box 2, Folder 2-58)
  - Water Wheel - Adjusting Waterwheel Shaft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-59)
  - Water Wheel - Turning 3000# Waterwheel Shaft, 1970 October (Box 2, Folder 2-60)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Shaft Mortise Boring, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-61)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Shaft Mortises, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-62)
  - Water Wheel - Mortise Waterwheel Shaft, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-63)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Shaft, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-64)
  - Greater Face Wheel - Mortise Greater Face Wheel Shaft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-65)
  - Greater Face Wheel - Bore Greater Face Wheel, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-66)
  - Water Wheel - Boring Waterwheel Shaft, 1970 November (Box 2, Folder 2-67)
  - CRM - Floor Joist, 1970 April (Box 2, Folder 2-68)
  - CRM - Floor Joist, 1970 April (Box 2, Folder 2-69)
  - CRM - Floor Joist, 1970 April (Box 2, Folder 2-70)
  - CRM - Joist, 1970 April (Box 2, Folder 2-71)
  - CRM - Joist, 1970 April (Box 2, Folder 2-72)
  - CRM - Lay Flooring, 1970 March (Box 2, Folder 2-73)
  - CRM - Stain Flooring, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-74)
  - CRM - Stain Flooring, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-75)
  - Resident Engineer - Cliff Currie in his Office, 1971 February (Box 2, Folder 2-76)
  - Water Wheel - Main Shaft, 1969 April (Box 2, Folder 2-77)
  - Resident Engineer - Currie & Hott Discuss Construction, 1971 May (Box 2, Folder 2-78)
  - Construction - Forebay Construction-Eston Watt, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-79)
  - Head Race, 1970 August (Box 2, Folder 2-80)
  - CRM - Forebay Layout, 1970 August (Box 2, Folder 2-81)
  - CRM - Forebay Construction, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-82)
  - CRM - Building Forebay, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-83)
  - CRM - Forebay Construction, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-84)
  - Water Wheel - Cliff Currie-Layout of Waterwheel, 1971 May (Box 2, Folder 2-85)
  - Water Wheel - Layout, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-86)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Layout, 1971 May (Box 2, Folder 2-87)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Layout, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-88)
  - Water Wheel - Construction of Waterwheel, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-89)
  - Water Wheel - Layout, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-90)
  - Water Wheel - Layout, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-91)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Layout - Arlington Millwork, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-92)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Layout - Arlington Millwork, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-93)
  - Water Wheel - Currie & Hott Discuss Waterwheel Construction, 1971 May (Box 2, Folder 2-94)
  - Water Wheel - Start Waterwheel Assembly, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-95)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Bucket Boards, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-96)
  - Water Wheel - Start Waterwheel Assembly, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-97)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Construction, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-98)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Construction, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-99)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Construction, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-100)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Construction, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-101)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel-Installing Rods, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-102)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Construction, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-103)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Construction, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-104)
  - Water Wheel - Currie-Waterwheel Construction, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-105)
  - Water Wheel - Currie-Waterwheel Construction, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-106)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Construction, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-107)
  - Water Wheel, 1971 November (Box 2, Folder 2-108)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Construction, 1971 November (Box 2, Folder 2-109)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Construction, 1971 November (Box 2, Folder 2-110)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Construction, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-111)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Construction, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-112)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel- Water Chute, 1972 January (Box 2, Folder 2-113)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel- Water Chute, 1972 January (Box 2, Folder 2-114)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Construction, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-115)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Arms in Place with Wedges, 1971 October (Box 2, Folder 2-116)
  - Water Wheel - Banding Waterwheel, 1971 November (Box 2, Folder 2-117)
  - Water Wheel - Banding Waterwheel Rims, 1971 November (Box 2, Folder 2-118)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Construction, 1971 November (Box 2, Folder 2-119)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Completed, 1972 January (Box 2, Folder 2-120)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Completed, 1971 November (Box 2, Folder 2-121)
  - CRM, 1971 November (Box 2, Folder 2-122)
  - Water Wheel - Waterwheel Completed, 1971 November (Box 2, Folder 2-123)
  - CRM - Capping Millstone, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-124)
  - CRM - Millstone Bed in Floor, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-125)
  - CRM - Setting Bed Millstone, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-126)
  - CRM - Greater Face Wheel Construction - Clifford Currie, 1971 May (Box 2, Folder 2-127)
  - CRM - Greater Face Wheel Arms Mortise, 1971 May (Box 2, Folder 2-128)
  - CRM - Currie - Greater Face Wheel Layout, 1971 May (Box 2, Folder 2-129)
  - CRM - Greater Face Wheel Construction, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-130)
  - CRM - Layout Greater Face Wheel, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-131)
  - CRM - Face Wheel Arms Center Layout, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-132)